

Profile

My passion is and always has been frontend development. I love the instant visual feedback that is unique to frontend development.

I am an open-source fanatic with over 280+ merged pull requests into many, many, many open-source repositories.

I have been a contributor of the month for Spotify's Backstage developer portal with 23+ merged pull-requests and I am now a code maintainer for the backstage repository.

I write professionally for Logrocket and my blog.

I have over 20+ years of experience working on some exceptional frontend pieces of work for companies such as

- The digital transformation of disclosure Scotland for both the basic disclosure and the PVG scheme digital online forms that replaced legacy or paper-based alternatives.
- Waitrose
- the Volvo Ocean race

At 53, I have more experience than most, and I get results in a fraction of the time.

Employment History

Frontend Developer at frontside, remote

February 2021 — July 2023

- React
- Typescript
- Nodejs
- Graphql
- · Spotify Backstage

Frontend Developer Contract at Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

August 2019 — December 2020

- Lead frontend developer on Scottish Governments pvg online https://csg.apply.disclosure.scot/
- helped set up the infrastructure for javascript/typescript development
- react
- typescript
- nodeis
- terraform
- AWS

Frontend Developer Contract at Screenmedia, Glasgow

June 2019 — August 2019

Frontend developer for clients of Screenmedia

Details

Glasgow United Kingdom 07908771391

paul.cowan@cutting.scot

Links

Github
Website
blog
twitter
linkedin

Skills

JavaScript

sales website

typescript

react

nodejs

ruby

CSS

HTML

d3/d3js

SASS/SCSS

Angular

Hobbies

Combat sports, boxing, MMA

- React
- typescript
- D3
- Node

Data Visualisations at Continuity2, Glasgow

April 2019 — June 2019

- Bringing data to life in the form of svg data visualisations
- react
- typescript
- d3

Contract Software Developer at Waracle, Glasgow, United Kingdom

January 2019 — April 2019

- Full-stack development for an online web portal with azure serverless technologies including blob storage and azure functions.
- Angular
- rxjs
- HTML 5, CSS, sass, Typescript
- · Azure (Blob storage, functions)
- Terraform

Frontend Developer Contract at BJSS - Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

June 2017 — December 2018

- Rewrite of the Scottish government disclosure Scotland online application forms for criminal record checks
- https://basic.apply.disclosure.scot/
- react
- typescript
- nodejs

Full Stack Contract Developer at WIPRO - Lloyds Bank, Edinburgh

November 2016 — June 2017

- Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal.
- react
- mobx
- webpack

Full Stack Contract Developer at City Holdings

March 2016 — November 2016

- Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal.
- react
- mobx
- webpack

Fullstack Contract Developer at Radium CRM Software, Glasgow

December 2012 — December 2015

Full Stack developer working on a CRM product called Radium.

· Emberjs frontend

- Migrated a ruby Sinatra app to ruby on rails on the backend
- Chrome extension development for Gmail
- · Hosted on Heroku

Full StackContract Developer at Continuity2, Glasgow

September 2007 — November 2012

- Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the Volvo ocean race.
- JQuery
- C# •

Full Stack Contract Developer at Twentysixlondon, London

March 2004 — August 2007

Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the volvo ocean race.

- C#
- ASP.NET

Education

Scottish Higher Maths - B, Further Education Anniesland, Glasgow

October 2015 — June 2016

Courses

◄ References

Richard McGlave from Continuity2

richard.mcglave@continuity2.com